Now that we learned F1 score,
我们已经学习了 F1 得分
我们再介绍一个更一般的概念
let's introduce something a bit more general. Here's the concept.
假设这是精度
If we have precision over here,
and recall over here,
这是召回率
F1 得分在二者中间
then F1 score is somewhere around the middle,
that gives as much importance to both.
二者的重要性是一样的
当然 如果其中一个更小
Of course if one of them is smaller,
it raises a flag but it treats them both the same.
则发出提醒 但同等对待二者
现在假设模型更关心精度
Now let's say our model cares a bit more about precision than recall.
那么我们希望更偏向于精度
Then we want something more skewed towards precision.
称其为 F0.5 得分
So we'll say it's F0.5 score.
叫做 β
So we call that beta.
β 是 0.5 β 越小
Beta is 0.5. The smaller the beta,
the more towards precision that we get.
就越接近精度
如果我们希望模型更关心召回率 则方向相反
Or if we want our model to care more about the recall than in the direction,
我们选择一个更大的 β 例如为 2
we pick a larger beta, say beta equals two.
因此指标是 F2
So our metric is F2.
If you like formulas, here they are.
如果想知道公式的话 公式如下
F1 得分是
Remember that the F1 score is two times precision,
2 * (精度*召回率）/(精度+召回率)
times recall, divided by precision plus recall.
对于 β 公式 只需在这里代入 β
So in the formula for beta, you just introduce a beta
over here that will skew your formula towards either
使公式偏向一个值或另一个值
取决于 β 很小或很大 我们来看看
one or the other one depending on if beta is small or large. So let's see.
If we have the fraud detection example,
对于欺诈检测示例
我们应该使用哪个 β？
which beta should we use?
I would initially think that this needs to be a high recall model since we need to catch
我一开始会认为需要是个高召回率模型
因为我们需要发现所有的欺诈情形
all the fraud cases and it's okay if we
可以检测并调查不是欺诈的情形
accidentally detect and investigate some that are not.
例如 F10
Something like F10.
But then maybe we're sacrificing too much precision and we accidentally sending
但或许精度降低了太多
我们不小心向客户发送了太多通知
our customers too many notifications
指出这些交易是欺诈性交易 但实际上并不是
about their transactions without them being fraudulent,
他们感到恼火了
and they're starting to get annoyed.
So we can move a bit toward say, F2.
我们可以降低下 例如设为 F2
But then maybe we would discover that we need to focus a bit more on
然后我们发现我们需要更侧重于召回率
recall because we really don't want to miss too many for two transactions,
因为我们不希望忽略太多的欺诈性交易
因此选择 F5
so we go here to F5.
这并不是一个精确的科学过程
It's not an exact science.
找到合适的 β 值需要对数据非常了解
Finding a good value of beta requires a lot of intuition of your data,
并且进行大量的实验
and a lot of experimentation.
现在我们做道测验 检测下所学的知识
Now let's test our knowledge and let's have a quiz.
So let's look at three possible models.
我们看看三个可能的模型
在第一种情形中 我们是 NASA
In the first one we are NASA and we have a model for
我们有一个检测飞船出故障零件的模型
detecting malfunctioning parts on a spaceship.
在第二种情形中 我们有一个视频推荐系统
In the second one, we have a video recommender system and we have a model
for sending users phone notifications of our new videos they may like.
我们有一个模型可以向用户发送短信通知 告诉他们可能喜欢的新视频
In the third one we are a store,
在第三种情形中 我们是一个店铺
and we have a model for sending free samples in the mail to potential clients.
我们有一个模型可以向潜在客户寄送免费样品
Let's say one of them has an F beta score of F1,
假设其中一个的 Fβ 得分为 F1
the other one is F0.5,
另一个是 F0.5
and the other one is F2.
另一个是 F2
Which one is which?
每个情形对应哪个得分？
Enter your answers below.
请将答案填在下方